Eduardo Costa

User Experience Specialist

CONTACT INFO

Eduardo Costa eduardo@torontobabel.com www.eduardo.work

ADVANCED SKILLS

UI/UX

Project management

HTML 5

CSS 3 with Flexbox

Responsive Web Design

SVG

jQuery

Bootstrap

Lightroom

Digital Photography

Sketch 3

InVision

GitHub

Unix for OS X

INTERMEDIATE SKILLS AND LEARNING

Photoshop

Illustrator

Javascript

LESS/SASS

JIRA

SQL

РНР

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

PERSONAL SUMMARY

UI/UX specialist with over 10 years of experience managing projects and a front-end developer.

Along with my career I have had the opportunity to work in projects for IBM, Embraer, small companies and Ontario government.

I have a passion for UI/UX and web design. And I am also a runner, meetup group organizer and photographer.

Here you can see a sample of my work: www.eduardo.work

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE IN CANADA

tudoaqui.ca

UI/UX Designer / Web developer 2011 - Current

- ★ Developed the entire responsive online newspaper using UI/UX techniques and methodologies
- ★ Coded the entire website over 100 pages using advanced HTML5, CSS3, LESS and DOM manipulation using JavaScript and jQuery
- ★ Worked with clients to meet their requirements and used Photoshop for wireframes and mock-ups
- ★ Used 5S approach: Strategy, Scope, Structure, Skeleton and Surface
- ★ Prepared styled emails for marketing campaigns (classifieds outreach and events)

Run Unlimited

Web developer / 2011 - 2014

- ★ Created a responsive e-commerce website using HTML5 and CSS3, logo, Flash animations
- ★ Set up hosting, domain registration and PayPal accounts

Ontario Ministry of Research and Innovation

Project Manager / 2010 – 2011

- ★ Led a project to build a database with innovation metrics currently tracked by international organizations
- ★ Consolidated information from an inter-ministries inquiry about Innovation Programs in Ontario
- ★ Assisted Strategic Planning team in developing performance measures for MRI programs

LATEST WEB DESIGN CERTIFICATIONS

User Experience Certificate - George Brown College

Currently enrolled

Specialization in UX/UI. This certificate provides a strong foundation in user experience (UX) design. Focused on advanced concepts of UX research and strategy, intuitive structure and best practices.

Web Design Certificate - OCAD, Toronto

Currently enrolled

Deeper understanding of web design, development, SEO and statistics in one of the best art schools of Canada.

Responsive Website Development and Design - University of London, UK

Currently enrolled

Six-month certification program. Learning about UX/UI, responsive websites, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Meteor.js, JQuery and databases

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Brazil

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering - 1999 UFMG is considered one of the best universities in Brazil.

UNA Management Sciences Faculty, Brazil

Graduate studies of Business Management - 1995 1st. place in admission exams, among over 2,000 candidates.